American Council for Polish Culture Collection. 1940-2013 CPAA 96-03
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain
American Council for Polish Culture Collection.
1940-2013
American Council for Polish Culture
CPAA 96-03
19 boxes (15 linear ft.)
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University
American Council for Polish Culture (ACPC) is one of the oldest Polish American cultural organizations. Beginning in 1948, and still existing today, the ACPC serves as a national umbrella organization for many local cultural clubs and organizations. The ACPC collection chronicles a wide range of the organization’s activities. It illustrates the beginning, changes and development of the organization supported with extensive correspondence, minutes, reports and annual conventions materials.
Historical Note
The American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs (ACPCC) was established, with its constitution and by-laws, in 1948 in Detroit during the fifth conference of Polish cultural clubs. Before this, there was a movement among Polish art and cultural clubs consisting of extensive discussions among Polonia's professionals and religious groups and community leaders about the importance of cultural sensitivity among Polish Americans. The main purpose was to promote cultural advancement among Polish American communities by providing information on cultural roots, creating a sense of pride of heritage, as well as preserving and popularizing cultural organizations, which served as ambassadors of Polish culture across the country. The Council is governed by officers and a board of directors elected at annual conventions.
The movement to promote and foster cultural awareness among Polish Americans began in the 1920's. The first cultural club, the Polish Arts Club of Chicago, was established in 1926. This was followed by Polanie in Minneapolis, Minn. 1927, Club Polonaise in Passaic, NJ in 1933, and the Polish Arts Club of Youngstown, OH in 1935. More formed later from informal cultural groups in various states. To foster better communication among these groups, the annual national conference was organized. The first one took place in New York City in 1939, then in Milwaukee in 1940, and Grand Rapids 1941. Annual conferences were interrupted by the war and several years later the 4th conference took place in Chicago in 1947. It was at this time that the formation of an organization on the national level was proposed and approved. For a short period of time, the name was changed to The American Council of Polish Cultural Organization (ACPCO); this was during Blanka Rosenstiel presidency (1984-1986). It was changed to reflect proposed changes in the mission of the organization, however it did not receive acceptance from all members and the name went back to The American Council for Polish Cultural Clubs. The name change from The American Council for Polish Cultural Clubs (ACPCC) to The American Council for Polish Culture (ACPC) was proposed in 1987 and became official in 1988 during the convention in Hartford, Connecticut, and it remains the official name till today. All three versions of the name are in use in various publications but it is still the same organization. The council accepts institutional and individual members and currently has about 250 members.
Main activities of the ACPC include organizing annual conventions, sponsoring lectures, musical recitals, poetry readings, art exhibits and awarding scholarships. Another important venue is publishing. From the very beginning communication among members was established with newsletters and bulletins. First publication was the National Polish Arts Bulletin in 1946 followed by The Quarterly Review of Polish Heritage and later the Polish Heritage, which still continues today. There was also an annual publication for conventions in form of anniversary pamphlets and annual reports. The council also contributes and supports publication of books and promotes exchange of cultural programs among affiliated clubs.
Scope and Content of the Collection
Collection consists of material covering years 1940-2013, which includes: administrative and general correspondence; convention programs, minutes and reports; various clubs activities. Also official publications for ACPC conventions and publications from affiliated members.
Arrangement
Mr. Charles A. Baretski was a member and archivist/historian of the organization for almost 30 years. He originally arranged the records and related material chronologically by date with the main focus on conventions as major undertaking of the organization each year. The Conventions were culminations of efforts by the governing body of the organization during their business sessions. Therefore as a wish of a donor, the original arrangement is kept within the collection.
The collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Connecticut Polish American Archives (CPAA) was selected as a repository for the papers of American Council of Polish Culture in 1990's. The first part of the papers was donated to the CPAA during a formal presentation in New Britain in December 1994. The second part of material was donated in 1996 and in 2001 seven boxes were donated by Gregory Biestek, a treasurer and archivist of ACPC. In 2013 material covering years 2003-2005 and 2010-2013 was sent to CPAA by the treasurer of the organization.
Related Material
For related material see the following collections:
Alfred F. Bochenek collection of American Council for Polish Culture records CPAA 02-01
Polish Cultural Club of Greater Hartford records CPAA 86-30
Joseph L. Zazyczny collection of American Council for Polish Culture records CPAA 99-15
Search Terms
Baretski, Charles A.; American Council for Polish Culture -- History.; American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs -- History.; Polish Americans -- Societies, etc.; Polish Americans -- History --Periodicals.; Polish Americans -- History -- 20th century.; Minutes.; Correspondence.; Anniversary publications.; Press releases.; Pamphlets.; Clippings.; Newsletters.
Container List
[The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.]
- Inventory
  - 2nd National Conference of Polish Arts Clubs, Milwaukee, Wisconsin., August, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Polish arts movement in the United States, article Tadeusz Slesinski, Dziennik Zwiazkowy., October 30, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National Polish Arts Bulletin, incomplete, Polish Arts Club, Chicago., 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - National Polish Arts Bulletin., 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence., 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 4th National Conference of Polish Art Clubs, report from convention by T.Slesinski, PAC Constitution, August, 7-9, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Czytelnia Polska, report 1889-1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Administrative correspondence., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ACPCC 5th National Conference, Detroit, - Constitution, final draft, proposed amendments by T. Slesinski., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ACPCC 5th National Conference - Telegram from Casimir Wierzynski with best wishes for the convention., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ACPCC Convention, Buffalo, NY - convention correspondence., August 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ACPCC Convention, Buffalo, NY - program, reports from clubs., August 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Constitution committee - proposed amendments., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - ACPCC Convention, Buffalo, NY - programs of events related to convention., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - ACPCC Convention committee- correspondence., 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Publicity for various clubs activities., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - ACPCC Convention, Wilkes Barre, PA - tentative program, publicity, President Dyczkowski address., July 1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ACPCC Convention, Wilkes Bare, PA - reports from various cultural clubs., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ACPCC Convention, Wilkes Bare, PA - programs and related material., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ACPCC Correspondence., 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ACPCC Publicity correspondence., 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - ACPCC Convention correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - ACPCC Convention, Alliance College, PA - programs and reports., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ACPCC Constitution., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, pt.1., 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, pt.2., 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, pt.3., 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, pt.4., 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - ACPCC Bulletins - Editor's correspondence., 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kultura project controversy - related correspondence., 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - ACPCC Board meeting minutes., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - ACPCC Convention, Alliance College - minutes., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - ACPCC Convention, Alliance College - reports and programs., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 13A)
  - ACPCC Constitution., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - ACPCC President's miscellaneous correspondence., 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - ACPCC Adam Mickiewicz project committee., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence compiled by Helen J. Sokolowska, an executive secretary., 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence compiled by Helen J. Sokolowska, an executive secretary., 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - ACPCC Literary contest correspondence., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - ACPCC Literary contest finances., 1953-1955 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - ACPCC Correspondence., 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - ACPCC Convention, Notre Dame University - programs and reports., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - ACPCC Convention, Notre Dame University - publicity, photograph and clippings., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - ACPCC Constitution with annotations and correspondence related to it., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - ACPCC Convention, Notre Dame University - program, reports, related material., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - ACPCC Money receipts., 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Polish Institute of Arts and Sciences of America - Mickiewicz fund raffle., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - ACPCC Correspondence, pt.1, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - ACPCC Correspondence, pt.2, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - ACPCC Correspondence, pt.3, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - ACPCC Correspondence, pt.4, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - ACPCC Correspondence, pt.5, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - ACPCC Correspondence, pt.6, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - ACPCC Treasurer's correspondence, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - ACPCC Publicity correspondence, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - ACPCC Mickiewicz project committee, correspondence., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Marcelina Sembrich voice contest-material used in contest., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Marcelina Sembrich voice contest - correspondence with The Sembrich Memorial Association., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Marcelina Sembrich voice contest-final audition., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Marcelina Sembrich voice contest-publicity., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Marcelina Sembrich voice contest-local auditions., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Marcelina Sembrich voice contest-applications., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Marcelina Sembrich voice contest-letters from clubs and individuals., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Marcelina Sembrich voice contest-general correspondence., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - ACPCC Convention, Seton Hall University - reports of individuals and committees., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - ACPCC Convention, Seton Hall University - Chairman's file., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - ACPCC Convention, Seton Hall University - reports, programs, constitution., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - ACPCC Convention, Seton Hall University - publicity., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - ACPCC Convention, Seton Hall University - constitution and proposed changes., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - ACPCC Circulars, notices, newsletters, reports., 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - ACPCC Convention - public relations., 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Catalog of Polish underground bulletins and publications of Solidarity support groups., 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - ACPCC Financial records., 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - ACPCC Report on treasurer's payment to executive secretary., 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - ACPCC Executive secretary correspondence, pt.1, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - ACPCC Executive secretary correspondence, pt.2, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - ACPCC Charles A. Baretski correspondence, programs, announcements., 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Buffalo- program drafts., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Buffalo - reports., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Buffalo - convention handouts., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Buffalo- correspondence., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Buffalo - speeches and presentations with notes., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Buffalo- minutes., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Buffalo - publicity., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Mickiewicz project committee - reports and correspondence., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Mickiewicz project committee - reports and correspondence, pt.1, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Mickiewicz project committee - reports and correspondence, pt.2, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - ACPCC President's correspondence., 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - ACPCC Constitution committee - notes., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Buffalo - registration material., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Buffalo - publicity., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Buffalo - documents, speeches, notes., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Buffalo - official souvenir program, reports from various clubs., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - ACPCC Convention, Northwestern University - reports, resolutions, events., 1956 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - ACPCC Convention, Northwestern University - information distributed to participants., 1956 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - ACPCC Convention, Northwestern University - minutes., 1956 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - ACPCC Convention, Northwestern University - publicity., 1956 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - ACPCC Executive correspondence, pt.1, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - ACPCC Executive correspondence, pt.2, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence., 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Letters to ACPCC President John Gembala from secretary Sylvia Hoynacki., 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Adam Mickiewicz project - correspondence, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - ACPCC Convention, Duquesne University, Pittsburgh - publicity., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - ACPCC Convention, Duquesne University, Pittsburgh - program, related material and events., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Charles A. Baretski correspondence related to ACPCC archives., 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - ACPCC President's correspondence., 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - ACPCC Newsletter., 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - ACPCC money receipts., 1954-1957 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence to promote historical record keeping by all clubs., 1955 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, A-D., 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, F-G., 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, H-J., 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, K., 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, L-R., 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, S., 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, T-Z., 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - ACPCC General correspondence, pt.1, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - ACPCC General correspondence, pt.2, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Rochester - program, reports, related events., 1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Rochester - publicity., 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - ACPCC Convention, Wilkes College - related events., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - ACPCC Convention, Wilkes College - programs and reports., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - ACPCC History committee correspondence., 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence., 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - ACPCC General correspondence., 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - ACPCC General correspondence., 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - ACPCC General correspondence., 1960 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - ACPCC General correspondence., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Minnesota - programs, reports., 1960 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - ACPCC Convention, University of Minnesota - related events., 1960 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - ACPCC Convention, Youngstown University - publicity., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - ACPCC Convention, Youngstown University - delegates information, reports, and related events., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - ACPCC Convention, Youngstown University - minutes which include correspondence, reports, publicity, souvenir book, programs and list of registrants., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - ACPCC Convention, Wayne State University - publicity., 1962 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - ACPCC Convention, Wayne State University - delegates information, registrants list., 1962 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - ACPCC Convention, Wayne State University - minutes which include correspondence, reports, publicity, souvenir book, programs., 1962 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - ACPCC Convention, Wayne State University - program and related events., 1962 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - ACPCC Convention, Wayne State University - programs, related events and publicity., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - ACPCC Convention, Marquette University - various reports and minutes., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - ACPCC Board meeting - minutes., January 1963 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence., 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence., 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - ACPCC - publicity., 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - ACPCC Convention, New York City - program, schedule and pamphlets., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - ACPCC Convention, New York City - related publications., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 1A)
  - ACPCC Convention, New York City - reports from various committees., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - ACPCC Convention, New York City - publicity., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - ACPCC Convention committee - credentials and administrative correspondence., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - ACPCC Board meetings, minutes, and reports., 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - ACPCC Ways and Means committee - correspondence., 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - ACPCC Constitution., 1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - ACPCC Convention Committee - credentials and administrative correspondence., 1965 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - ACPCC Convention, Alliance College - program, pamphlets, registration list., 1965 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - ACPCC Convention, Alliance College - reports., 1965 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - ACPCC Convention, Alliance College - publicity., 1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - ACPCC Correspondence and ballots related to selection site for the next convention., 1965 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - ACPCC Board meeting - reports and minutes., 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - ACPCC Convention committee - credentials and administrative correspondence., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - ACPCC Nomination committee - correspondence., 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - ACPCC Correspondence related to National Poster Contests., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence., 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - ACPCC Convention, John Fisher College - publicity., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - ACPCC Convention, John Fisher College - reports, list of participants., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - ACPCC Convention, John Fisher College - material distributed to delegates., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - ACPCC Convention, John Fisher College - program, related events., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence., 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - ACPCC Convention committee credentials and administrative correspondence., 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - ACPCC Correspondence and ballots about acceptance of second affiliate in Chicago., 1967 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - ACPCC Executive board meeting minutes., 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - ACPCC Convention, Washington, DC - reports, minutes, correspondence., 1967 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - ACPCC Convention, Washington DC - publicity., 1967 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - ACPCC National convention - correspondence., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - ACPCC stamp project for Maria Sklodowska-Curie., 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - ACPCC convention committee credentials., 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - ACPCC Convention, Duquesne University - treasurer's records., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - ACPCC Convention planning notes., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - ACPCC Convention - program book committee., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence., 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - ACPCC Treasurer's notes., 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - ACPCC Convention, Duquesne University - publicity., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - ACPCC Treasurer's report., 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - ACPCC Convention, Duquesne University - minutes, reports., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - ACPCC Convention, Duquesne University - list of registrants, souvenir program., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - ACPCC Convention committee - credentials., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - ACPCC Board meeting minutes and reports., 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence., 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - ACPCC Treasurer's notes., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - ACPCC Treasurer's correspondence., 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - ACPCC Awards Committee., 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - ACPCC Convention, Alliance College - minutes, reports, official program., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - ACPCC Treasurer's correspondence., 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - ACPCC Treasurer's notes., 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - ACPCC Publicity., 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, pt.1., 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, pt.2., 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - ACPCC Legal matters., 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - ACPCC Convention committee - credentials and correspondence., 1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - ACPCC Executive board minutes., 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - ACPCC Convention, Alliance College - reports from various committees and clubs., 1970 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - ACPCC Convention, Alliance College - publicity report, official programs., 1970 (Box 9, Folder 16A)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, pt.1., 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, pt.2., 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - ACPCC Administrative correspondence, pt.3., 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - ACPCC President's newsletter., 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - ACPCC Treasurer's notes., 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - ACPCC Legal matters - incorporation, tax exemption status., 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - ACPCC Correspondence related to controversy with editor of Quarterly Review., 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - ACPCC Board minutes and reports., 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - ACPCC Convention, Orchard Lake Schools - reports., 1971 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - ACPCC Convention, Orchard Lake Schools - information folder., 1971 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - ACPCC Convention, Orchard Lake Schools - publicity, clippings, official programs, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 26A)